Omer Ali Abdallh

Software engineer

🗣 Dubai, United Arab Emirates 🛛 Omeralis2000@gmail.com 📞 +971582112250 🛚 in linkedin.com/in/omer-ali-510721190

nttps://github.com/omeralis Rersonal Website

Profile

Having 5 years of IT experience in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) preparation requirements. Front-end infrastructure development using HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery TypeScript, good experiences in developing Angular framework for single page application, and other design library based on JavaScript. Highly skilled in back-end and create web services components for restful web services to interact with user interfaces using REST API with Laravel framework.

Skills

Front-end Frameworks and Libraries

HTML &CSS ,Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript Angular Frameworks, Responsive design.

SQL & MySQL and Oracle Database

basics in design Software

Back-end Frameworks

Laravel (PHP)

Version control

Git on GitHub, GitLab & Microsoft Teams

Adobe XD and Figma

Professional Experience

Jan 2018 - present Khartoum, sudan

Sabq Charity Organization

Software Development

Provide technical support to the organization.

Aug 2019 - Jan 2022 Khartoum, Sudan

Oasis computer System

Full Stack Developer

- Worked on the architecture and development of an insurance aggregator application providing service to more than 5000 clients.
- Worked on the architecture and development of dashboards and control panels for the customers to manage and keep track of their products and services provided by them.
- Worked on developing and implementing of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker system to replace the existing desktop version.
- Maintained and refactored legacy applications, improving their performance by more than 30%.
- Building new Angular components for the customer-facing web app.
- Interfaced with 5 customers per month to gather requirements and resolve issues.
- Presided over a 30% increase in repeat business.

Nov 2018 - Aug 2020

Khartoum, Sudan

Afromony

Full Stack Developer

- Developing electronic payment system (Morsal Core) and solving problems, in addition to developing websites and electronic payment systems.
- Implemented the Integration with customers that provide online payments services (Restful APIs).
- Worked on the architecture and development of dashboards and control panels.

Feb 2019 - Jul 2020 Khartoum, Sudan

Antalya Company

Full Stack Developer

- Worked on the architecture and development of a web-based Medical Consultant Broker.
- Designed, analyze and implementing the dashboard for the Medical Consultant Broker.
- Creating and maintaining the server-side API.

Jan 2018 - Feb 2019

Khartoum, Suadn

Khartoum, Sudan

Mar 2021

Sudan University of Science and Technology - Admission and Registration Deanship Admission and Registration Deanship (Department of Card)

Specialized Medical Insurance Company

Front-End Development

Part Time

Education

Mar 2013 - Dec 2017 Khartoum, Sudan

Bachelor's degree in Management Information System

Sudan University of Science and Technology

Projects

Morsel Payment (CMS)

Development and maintain of a web-based payment report system for Morsal Core.

Medical Insurance System

Afromoney

Consist of two applications for Khartoum State Health Insurance Authority that help the service providers and insured. A web-based application to help the service providers to keep track and manage their claims payments. Also, an application for the insured members to help them get the services from providers and pay for these services using his electronic payment card. Worked on designing, analyze and implementing the front-end and back-end.

1 / 2 Omer Ali Abdallh

Salary App

Afromoney

Online batch payment system that provides an easy way to pay for multi beneficiaries. Worked on designing and implement the front-end and back-end.

HR System

Employee life management system and everything related to financial aspects Laravel & Angular

Stock Management System

Point of Sale system

Angular, Laravel

Applus Insurance Aggregator - KSA 🛮

Insurance Brokerage Aggregator

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the customers get the quotations, compare and buy online policies for their vehicles, travels, and medical malpractice. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

AlMamoon Insurance Aggregator- KSA

Insurance Brokerage Aggregator

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the customers get the quotations, compare and buy online policies for their vehicles, travels, and medical malpractice. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Insurance Broker System (IBS) - KSA 🗹

Insurance Broker System

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker system to replace the existing desktop version.

Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Concord-Aggregator-UI-Admin- KSA 🗹

Admin dashboard Concord Aggregator Insurance

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the broker keep track of all clients quotations, policies, claims, requests and complaints. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Applus-Aggregator-UI-Admin- KSA

Admin dashboard Applus Aggregator Insurance

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the broker keep track of all clients quotations, policies, claims, requests and complaints. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

Almamoon-Aggregator-UI-Admin- KSA

Admin dashboard Almamoon Aggregator Insurance

Development of a fully integrated web-based insurance broker aggregator, to help the broker keep track of all clients quotations, policies, claims, requests and complaints. Worked on designing and implement the front-end.

A References

Eng. Muizz Mohammed Mahdy, Software Engineer, Oasis Computer Systems Muizzmahdy@gmail.com, +249118441017

Eng. Akram Gorashi Sayed, *Software Engineer*, Oasis Computer Systems akramgorashi6@hotmail.com, +249925050905

Eng. Tariq Mansour, Technical Department Manager, Afromony +249912356709

Eng. Issara Mohmmed, *General Director*, Sabg Organization +249123273808

Eng. Yassin Eltaype, $Team\ Manager$, Oasis Computer System +971585966304

Omran Ibrahim, *Team Manager*, Oasis Computer System omranibrahim30@gmail.com, +249993061298

Omer Ali Abdallh 2 / 2